<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Contributor Experience Handbook</title>
<link>https://contributor-experience.org/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://contributor-experience.org/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.3.450</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Documenting paths to leadership in open-source projects</title>
  <dc:creator>Melissa Weber Mendonça</dc:creator>
  <link>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/leadership/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="what-is-leadership" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-is-leadership">What is leadership?</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Transparent processes for becoming a decision-maker in open source help foster trust. Today, just 37% of all respondents surveyed agree that there are clear processes to become a leader or maintainer in an open source project. Language barriers may exacerbate clarity, as those preferring German, Spanish, Portuguese, and French were all more likely to disagree. Meanwhile, respondents from the Asia-Pacific region, Middle East, and Africa were more likely to see clarity in the path to leadership than the study average. These trends were reiterated when asked whether respondents felt they had a visible leadership role in open source. Unfortunately (though not surprisingly), those with no reliable Internet access are less likely to hold visible leadership positions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><em><a href="https://8112310.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/8112310/LF%20Research/2021%20DEI%20Survey%20-%20Report.pdf">Linux Foundation DEI Report 2021</a></em></p>
<p>There are many flavors of open-source project governance. From the “Benevolent Dictator for Life” (BDFL) to the Steering council models there is a spectrum of policies and decision-making processes that are meant to organize the work and (ideally) build trust in these communities - including giving people clarity on how they can be a part of the “core” group of decision-makers.</p>
<p>Despite being open and “democratic”, one can very easily detect a problem: while the entire open-source culture lacks diversity in its ranks, the situation is even more dire in positions of leadership. There are many discussions about why this is so, including considering existing societal power structures reflected in open-source governance. The “tyranny of structurelessness” [2, 3] thesis by feminist theorist Jo Freeman is particularly popular, and states that in the absence of explicit project rules and governance structures, implicit ones take over.</p>
<p>For underrepresented people, explicitly stating what they need to achieve to reach a certain role in the project is extremely important. It signals you don’t have to be a part of a certain club to be considered for leadership, and that it is worth participating. Not being in the same timezone, not being part of the same culture, not speaking the same language, not having the same background - all of these differences accumulate for an individual but may be invisible to an outsider.</p>
</section>
<section id="power-and-responsibilities" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="power-and-responsibilities">Power and responsibilities</h2>
<p>Open-source projects are not all the same. Each project has its own internal organization and structure (explicitly or implicitly). For folks who are joining, this distribution of power and responsibilities may not be obvious, and may pose a barrier to participation. If I’m not sure who to ask for commit rights, how can I ever feel comfortable in a project?</p>
<p>Even in the most horizontal of projects, being a maintainer effectively means something. It can start with commit rights, but it also means having some sort of expectations for participation, be it meetings, code reviews, documentation, code or onboarding new contributors. Spelling this out is helpful both for newcomers and for folks coming from other projects which organize themselves differently.</p>
<p>There is also something in it for the maintainers: if not only power but responsibilities can be shared, hopefully there is less space for burnout, the burden of making decisions is lowered, and the increased sense of community and trust in meaningful participation creates a sense of ownership and shared purpose.</p>
</section>
<section id="isnt-this-gatekeeping" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="isnt-this-gatekeeping">Isn’t this gatekeeping?</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>There’s a lot of great work on creating inclusive and welcoming communities in open source. But I think one of the most effective ways to approach community building is through the lens of pathways to leadership. A path that invests in new maintainers is the backbone of creating a welcoming, diverse, and sustainable open source community. <a href="https://medium.com/@abbycabs/creating-pathways-that-invest-in-new-maintainers-8ffb52e09681">Abigail Cabunoc-Mayes, <em>“Creating Pathways That Invest in New Maintainers”</em></a></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Can too much structure be harmful? Many people would see attempts at organizing roles within a project as gatekeeping, since the idea of ticking checkboxes for participation is not appealing in a culture that encourages open participation and prides itself on self-organization.</p>
<p>This can be true if rules are applied too strictly or if people don’t trust leaders to step down so that others can step in. Each community will have its own understanding of how to organize itself, but there is reasonable evidence to support the idea that if there are no rules, the louder person in the room will end up making all the decisions and push away diverse thought. If we require people to step up in a system that doesn’t make space for them, we are setting them up for failure.</p>
<p>What are your examples of open-source projects with good structure? Come to our <a href="https://contributor-experience.zulipchat.com/join/wgjnyihfd74iflbfpnuabqag/">zulip chat</a> and share your thoughts!</p>
</section>
<section id="links" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="links">Links</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li><a href="https://github.com/programminghistorian/jekyll/wiki/Privileges-and-Responsibilities-of-Membership">Programming historian: Privileges and Responsibilities of Membership</a></li>
<li><a href="https://8112310.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/8112310/LF%20Research/2021%20DEI%20Survey%20-%20Report.pdf">Hilary Carter and Jessica Groopman, “Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion in Open Source: Exploring the Challenges and Opportunities to Create Equity and Agency Across Open Source Ecosystems,” foreword by Jim Zemlin, The Linux Foundation, December, 2021.</a></li>
<li><a href="https://builtin.com/software-engineering-perspectives/economy-governance-open-source">Open-Source Governance, Meet Feminist Economics</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.jofreeman.com/joreen/tyranny.htm">Jo Freeman, “The Tyranny of Structurelessness”</a></li>
<li><a href="https://medium.com/@abbycabs/creating-pathways-that-invest-in-new-maintainers-8ffb52e09681">Abigail Cabunoc Mayes, “Creating Pathways That Invest in New Maintainers”</a></li>
<li><a href="https://igorwiese.com/images/papers/CSCW2020.pdf">Trinkenreich, Guizani et al, “Hidden Figures: Roles and Pathways of Successful OSS Contributors”</a></li>
<li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2103.11007">Jean-Gabriel Young, Amanda Casari, Katie McLaughlin, Milo Z. Trujillo, Laurent Hébert-Dufresne, James P. Bagrow, Which contributions count?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2008.04236">PolicyKit: Building governance in online communities</a></li>
<li><a href="https://opensource.guide/best-practices/">Open Source Guides: Best Practices for Maintainers</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/readme/guides/maintainer-monolith">Breaking apart the monolith: The Open Source movement should really be modeled after social clubs and city governments</a></li>
<li><a href="https://communitywiki.org/wiki/DoOcracy">Do-ocracy</a></li>
</ol>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/leadership/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Fostering an Inclusive Culture: Call for Participation</title>
  <dc:creator>Marco Gorelli, May Ireland, Melissa Mendonça, Inessa Pawson, Noa Tamir, Pamphile Roy</dc:creator>
  <link>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/dei-report/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Have you often wondered how decisions get made across scientific open source projects? Communications sometimes a little ‘off’? Think we can do better? Then now’s the time to get involved.</p>
<p>Most folks who have been involved with open-source communities have thoughts and ideas about what we can do to be more inclusive and welcoming. However, rarely do we get a chance to have these conversations and express our points of view in a constructive, collaborative way.</p>
<p>As part of our <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/online_resource/Advancing_an_inclusive_culture_in_the_scientific_Python_ecosystem/16548063">CZI grant to Advance an Inclusive Culture in the scientific Python ecosystem</a>, we (maintainers and contributors to NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib and pandas) have been working in collaboration with <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/mayireland">May Ireland</a> to create a report with areas that are top of mind when we talk about improving our projects’ cultures and being more inclusive. We want to be more intentional about attracting, supporting and retaining people from diverse backgrounds to join as contributors.</p>
<p>As a result of this report, we should like to focus on how we communicate with each other, resolve disputes and make more informed decisions. We’ll soon be kicking off a series of DEI Culture Labs to work on these three areas, and we would like to invite participation from members of our communities, whether already engaged with the projects or not. We would love to hear your ideas and understand what we can do differently.</p>
<p><a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1pxSte5_M8-dZftFTPDxfaBwubJlDoCEb/view?usp=share_link">Read the DEI Insights Report</a> and find out how you can help! You can also <a href="https://contributor-experience.zulipchat.com/join/wgjnyihfd74iflbfpnuabqag/">sign up here</a> to the Contributor Experience Zulip chat, which is the communication channel we will be using for these conversations.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/dei-report/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What is the difference between Contributor Experience and Community Management?</title>
  <dc:creator>Melissa Mendonça, Inessa Pawson, Noa Tamir</dc:creator>
  <link>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/cel-cm/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>While the role of <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/blog/many-faces-community-manager">community manager</a> is established in the open source ecosystem, the role of a Contributor Experience lead is not yet well defined. Even though there is prior work in contributor experience (for example, the <a href="https://github.com/kubernetes/community/blob/master/sig-contributor-experience/README.md">Contributor Experience working group within the Kubernetes community</a>), our team has been working to develop an understanding of what this work means in our communities. In this post, we will explain our perceptions and the differences between contributor experience and community management.</p>
<p>To be clear, there is indeed a bit of overlap. Many of the activities that these roles involve are currently not owned by anyone in particular in most open-source projects; they are being done by overworked, overstretched developers and maintainers who just want to see more people get involved with their projects. That is also the case for the projects we are working on - except for Matplotlib, none of them have a community manager role. This makes us sometimes fill two positions, which is indeed a lot!</p>
<p>Due to the undefined nature of roles in most open-source projects, we often see many different roles being shared by community members instead of concentrated on one person. This is not necessarily bad - in fact, for small open-source projects this may be the only reasonable way to operate. But defining responsibilities and tasks within the project may help organize the work and open new pathways for contributions beyond code.</p>
<section id="focus-on-contributors" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="focus-on-contributors">Focus on contributors</h2>
<p>One big difference between what we think of as community managers and a contributor experience team member is that it is common to think of the community manager as someone that will bring new users or do promotion for the project, raising awareness of its existence and only maybe down the line indirectly attract new contributors. For the contributor experience team, the focus is primarily on the contributor community, onboarding and providing better tools and workflows for new contributors, as well as supporting maintainers in their interactions with the contributor community.</p>
</section>
<section id="the-t-word" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="the-t-word">The “T” word</h2>
<p>While this work involves <em>a lot</em> of social interaction and engagement, a contributor experience role requires reasonable <em>technical skills</em> to help onboard newcomers, provide tooling and automation, and <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_experience#Developer_experience">Developer Experience</a> improvements to the project. These are typically not required of community managers but are critical to the contributor experience work.</p>
</section>
<section id="advocates-for-new-contributors" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="advocates-for-new-contributors">Advocates for new contributors</h2>
<p>If this role had <em>one</em> job, it would be to ensure new contributors are adequately onboarded into an open-source project and that they see a clear pathway into long-term collaboration and contribution to the community. This could involve defining new and diverse roles in the community, documentation of current pathways, and better workflows to support engagement in the project. But this also involves some human connection - understanding why people want to contribute, how they want to engage, and how we can make that experience better for them.</p>
</section>
<section id="governance-and-change-management" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="governance-and-change-management">Governance and change management</h2>
<p>Another focus point of our contributor experience work is ensuring governance, and internal decisions are well-documented and well-defined. This is particularly important to create a culture of equal participation and inclusion. This can also involve some <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Change_management">change management</a> to help the community through necessary transitions. In this sense, the contributor experience lead has a position that is independent of maintainer status or leadership involvement.</p>
</section>
<section id="collaboration-with-community-managers" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="collaboration-with-community-managers">Collaboration with Community Managers</h2>
<p>We see the Contributor Experience and Community Management areas as complimentary; while the former focuses on contributions and internal processes, the latter can focus on communications, outreach, social media, and program development for the larger community. Receiving feedback and understanding what users expect of an open-source project can also help define roadmaps and priorities for contribution.</p>
</section>
<section id="what-do-you-think" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-do-you-think">What do you think?</h2>
<p>We would love to hear from you - what do <em>you</em> think could be involved in this work?</p>
<p>We hope to create a <a href="https://www.communityofpractice.ca/background/what-is-a-community-of-practice/">community of practice</a> around the contributor experience work and to open a more extensive discussion about the place this work has in existing (and new) open-source projects. If you want to talk about it, we host <a href="https://scientific-python.org/calendars/">weekly community calls on Zoom</a>. Anyone is welcome to join, chat, or just listen. Hope to see you around!</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/cel-cm/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Advancing an inclusive culture in the scientific Python ecosystem</title>
  <dc:creator>Melissa Mendonça, Inessa Pawson, Noa Tamir</dc:creator>
  <link>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/cel-year-one/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>In August 2021, NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, and pandas were awarded a 2-year joint grant by the CZI EOSS program. The goal of this work, citing the <a href="https://figshare.com/articles/online_resource/Advancing_an_inclusive_culture_in_the_scientific_Python_ecosystem/16548063">grant proposal</a>, is</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>To support the onboarding, inclusion, and retention of people from historically marginalized groups on scientific Python projects and structurally improve the community dynamics of NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, and pandas.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is an ambitious project, and we are well aware that diversity, equity and inclusion issues in open source are numerous [<a href="https://www.linuxfoundation.org/research/the-2021-linux-foundation-report-on-diversity-equity-and-inclusion-in-open-source">1</a>, <a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/06/diversity-open-source-even-worse-tech-overall/">2</a>, <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/codeswitch/2013/12/05/248791579/why-isnt-open-source-a-gateway-for-coders-of-color">3</a>, <a href="">4</a>] and that proposed solutions [<a href="https://allinopensource.org/">1</a>, <a href="https://press.princeton.edu/books/hardcover/9780691182070/hacking-diversity">2</a>, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=THf8_A-RK38">3</a>] are not necessarily straightforward. However, we decided to propose a few actions that could have an impact on how our communities engage with newcomers, especially those from underrepresented and historically marginalized groups. We also wanted to explore and document how these open-source projects are organized, and find potential areas for improvement. In this post, we discuss a few of the initiatives we have worked on so far, and some key take aways, which we wanted to share early.</p>
<section id="what-we-did-so-far" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="what-we-did-so-far">What we did so far</h2>
<p>Our team is made up of three <em>Contributor Experience Leads</em>: Melissa Mendonça (SciPy/Matplotlib), Inessa Pawson (NumPy), and Noa Tamir (Matplotlib/pandas). We started working across the four projects at different times, and quickly also realized that each project had different needs and was organized differently. We prioritized working with the maintainers to build a shared understanding of our goals and proposed actions.</p>
<section id="community-engagement-meetings-and-communication-channels" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="community-engagement-meetings-and-communication-channels">Community engagement: meetings and communication channels</h3>
<p>In the book <a href="https://press.stripe.com/working-in-public">Working in Public: The Making and Maintenance of Open Source Software</a>, Nadia Eghbal classifies open-source projects by rate of user growth and contributor growth. The four open-source projects we are working on are <a href="https://project-types.github.io/#stadium">stadiums</a> according to this model, which means that interacting with the maintainers is perceived as out-of-reach or intimidating. Many people fear having their newbie questions immortalized on GitHub or other public forums, and avoid contributing for fear of having their code criticized too harshly.</p>
<p>Many projects, including NumPy and Matplotlib, already had established meetings to discuss technical and community topics or coordinate working groups. Our team worked with all four projects and collaborated with the <a href="scientific-python.org/">Scientific Python project</a> to recommend (<a href="https://learn.scientific-python.org/maintainers/meeting_types/">and document</a>) meeting types, as well as <a href="https://scientific-python.org/calendars/">community events calendars</a>. We have also worked on creating meeting notes templates [<a href="https://hackmd.io/@matplotlib/SJ3oc8oqq">Matplotlib</a>, <a href="https://github.com/numpy/archive/blob/main/numpy-meetings-glossary.md">NumPy</a>] and archiving procedures wherever possible.</p>
<p>We have also created Slack workspaces for SciPy and pandas as additional communication channels for new contributors to connect with projects’ core developers and other project contributors. (NumPy and Matplotlib already have been using Slack and Gitter respectively). For NumPy, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/c/NumPy_team">a number of videos were produced for the NumPy YouTube channel</a> that serve as onboarding documentation for new contributors. We hope to expand this initiative to other projects.</p>
</section>
<section id="onboarding" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="onboarding">Onboarding</h3>
<p>From a sustainability point of view, onboarding new contributors and helping them make their way through the project is an important activity that requires time, resources and flexibility to understand why people engage with open-source projects and what makes them stay. Often, there is implicit, undocumented knowledge and processes that are hard to understand for those looking to join as contributors (and even for existing contributors when they want to transition into other roles in the project).</p>
<p>We started by reviewing and suggesting improvements to the contributor onboarding guides for each of the four projects. We have been gathering feedback from our communities and new contributors on points that are still confusing, unclear or not explicit in our current documentation.</p>
<p>However, documentation is often not enough. We have been working to also help people directly by answering questions, understand their needs in each project and figure out how they can have a good experience when contributing. All four projects now have regular “newcomer” or “new contributor” meetings, dedicated to folks who are curious about contributing, who need help with technical issues or review on their pull requests, or who want to find different ways to engage with our projects.</p>
</section>
<section id="outreach-sprints-talks-and-other-activities" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="outreach-sprints-talks-and-other-activities">Outreach: sprints, talks, and other activities</h3>
<p>Participating in sprints and other outreach activities such as talks, live coding events, or events targeting historically underrepresented groups in open source is something we are actively trying to do. Here is a list of activities we participated in during the first year of the grant:</p>
<ul>
<li>Sprints organized as part of the <a href="https://hackmd.io/9pfJGVlVSVKKOQgCFsjqLQ">PyCon US</a> and <a href="https://www.scipy2022.scipy.org/sprints-schedule">SciPy US</a> conferences.</li>
<li>Sprint at Grace Hopper Celebration “Open Source Day”</li>
<li>A video presented for DataUmbrella detailing how to navigate the SciPy codebase</li>
</ul>
<p>and several other talks/presentations (detailed at the end of the post).</p>
<p>With sprints, our goal is to not only help folks get started with contributing, but also to gather feedback from the community on contributing guides and process. We also use this feedback to evaluate and track the impact of sprints in our contributor base.</p>
<p>Presenting talks and showing our work is also a way to (i) get the word out that this kind of work is happening and folks can do this; (ii) inspire maintainers to be leaders in their communities; (iii) encourage contributors, by showing that we can support them and they are not alone.</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="plans-for-the-next-half" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="plans-for-the-next-half">Plans for the next half</h2>
<p>We still have a lot to do, and for the next half of the grant period we want to focus on a few additional areas.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p><strong>Processes</strong> Although many of our communities and projects have spontaneously grown from one person or a small group of people to huge projects, many of the decisions still rely on a lot of “common sense” practices and implicit rules. We are looking to document a few of those to make it more explicit to newcomers and to be clear about responsibilities, expectation and how to benefit from open source contributions (after all, each contributor also has their legitimate reasons for joining our projects, be it notes on their CVs, professional networking, some form of personal gratification or just feeling like they are part of some <em>community</em>). In that sense, we have started creating documents such as a <a href="https://numpy.org/devdocs/dev/reviewer_guidelines.html?highlight=inactive#for-maintainers">policy on inactive PRs for NumPy</a>, and <a href="">a document on how to triage issues for SciPy</a> and others (such as how to become a maintainer of these projects) are still in progress.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Multiple pathways</strong> Many different skills (beyond just code) are needed to keep large open-source projects working: documentation, website support, issue triaging, translations, fundraising, etc. We are working to establish and document pathways for new contributors to progress to these specific areas of a projects’s maintenance.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Metrics</strong> One of the issues we have encountered is identifying appropriate metrics and responsible ways of gathering information about contributors to study projects’ demographic make up and track progress in our DEI efforts. We have been researching how other OSS projects approach this challenge and are devising an action plan to address it.</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="learning" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="learning">Learning</h2>
<p>This kind of work requires trust, human connections and respect, and is often made invisible by the simplistic metrics we use to gauge contributions in open-source projects. This discussion would be worth a blog post on its own (more to come in the future!)</p>
<p>In 3 of the 4 project we joined as new contributors ourselves, which presented challenges as we needed to learn how the project works, and we weren’t immediately empowered to make decisions. Issues involving governance, communication and leadership are challenging to tackle, and we are particularly grateful to be working with a supportive team of leaders who are with us every step of the way. We have built new working relationships and are becoming more and more active in the projects as we open new pathways for the community to grow.</p>
<section id="resources" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="resources">Resources</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lQWDRg99B6w">Beyond the Basics: Contributor Experience, Diversity and Culture in Open Source Projects</a> - Keynote at PyData Berlin/PyCon DE (Melissa Mendonça)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V1FCSijy460">Contributing to SciPy</a> - SciPy contributor onboarding video for DataUmbrella (Melissa Mendonça)</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/noatamir/Talks/blob/master/PyDataBer2022-ContributorExperienceLeads.pdf">What is Contributor Experience? &amp; how do you lead it?</a> - presented by Noa Tamir at PyData Berlin meetup</li>
<li><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/inessapawson/introducing-the-contributor-experience-lead-team-at-scipy-2022">Contributor Experience Lead team introduction</a> (<a href="https://github.com/InessaPawson/scipy_proceedings/blob/2022/SciPy'22%20–%20CEL%20team%20–%20Inessa%20Pawson.pdf">PR to the conference proceedings</a>) - presented by Inessa Pawson at SciPy US 2022 Tools Plenary Session</li>
<li><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/inessapawson/numpy-update-on-the-project-at-scipy-2022">Annual update on the NumPy project</a> (<a href="https://github.com/scipy-conference/scipy_proceedings/tree/2022/presentations/tools/numpy">PR to the conference proceedings</a>) - presented by Inessa Pawson at SciPy US 2022 Tools Plenary Session</li>
<li><a href="https://speakerdeck.com/inessapawson/contributing-to-numpy-a-roadmap-for-newcomers">Contributing to NumPy: a roadmap for newcomers</a> - presented by Inessa Pawson at the Data for Good Regina monthly meeting on Jun 28, 2022</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/numpy/archive/tree/main/newcomers_meetings">NumPy Newcomers’ Hour documentation</a></li>
<li><a href="https://matplotlib.org/stable/devel/contributing.html#new-contributors-meeting">New contributors meeting documentation (Matplotlib)</a> and <a href="https://github.com/matplotlib/ProjectManagement/tree/master/new_contributor_meeting/2022">meeting notes</a></li>
</ul>


</section>
</section>

 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/cel-year-one/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hello World</title>
  <dc:creator>Noa Tamir</dc:creator>
  <link>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/Hello-world/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Welcome to our blog! We welcome community contributions about your work and thoughts regarding Contributor Experience. Or maybe you have a call to the community, or would like to start a discussion with more than 240 characters 😉. Think of this as a place to have longer public conversations about how the social infrastructure of open source projects.</p>
<p>If you’d like ot have less public conversations. We will soon launch community meetings. Check out our <a href="../../../docs/about/calendar.html">calendar</a>. Our <a href="../../../docs/about/comms_channels.html">communication channels</a> will be updated shortly as well.</p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://contributor-experience.org/docs/posts/Hello-world/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
